we're at homeosoma electella yes thank you guys sorry i have to run away sure
this is another sunflower boss and
for some reason it's a variable species but the western ones around here are all kind of
glossy looking and look different but ones that i collected early in the year
look like ones from out of our area which are more uh kind of granular looking i don't know how to
expect they look like sand you know desert sand or something rather than shiny and somewhat tan
but it turns out there's a second species here called homeosoma oslorellum
okay and in dissecting most many of those earlier gray ones yeah i'll be there in about 10 minutes
um in dissecting most many of those earlier gray ones
they turned out to be oslorellum and may have been recorded as uh electoa oh so do not trust but i
save most of them so it may be possible to go back and determine whether they are oslorellum or
electilla and i saved them because they did look so different than the shinier moth um that tends to
fly later in the year or at least build up in numbers until later in the year
so that's something that we can put on the back burner
but you know in the first monograph on visa times the author of that commented that there was lots of
different forms of electella but he may not have realized that there was more than one species when he
he made that comment hyleus phyleus hyalephala phyleus is a skipper a butterfly it's native
but it's a lawn moth so it seems to be found in urban areas on lawns
uh and it turns up on light at light on hot nights as long as well as a very similar looking lawn moth
that is probably native whereas this i'm less sure as native i don't know art could probably
give you more information on the skippers the other one is that atalapides campestras
which we may have i don't know whether you included it or not
it would only be at davis i never got skippers at cold canyon at light yeah i don't think that one was
included
no atalapides was not in there
though it may not be an atalapides anymore butterfly taxonomy is like changes all the time chasing a
dragonfly you just can't catch it
okay where was i
the skipper ohyleus lineata
that's a syngid that's the line sphinx white line sphinx yeah yeah and it migrates out of
deserts particularly in drought years and when it does it shows up in a
a mostly early in the year and um with a greater range of size than when it's non-migratory
so
greater numbers may indicate drought and desert areas
i mean i've been in places in southern california where the caterpillars are like
teeming all over the place everywhere you walk so it's just crazy uh and then they migrate because
they in bad years or caterpillars outnumber food sources they're out of town the sinopolia olivacea
um i need to confirm the identity because there's another species which i first reported last year
the name of which i can't recall off the top of my head
the illustrations of the genitalia are available so i would be able to confirm it
but i haven't been getting this in recent years as frequently as greg has in his yard but this
is one of those species that flies late and now with more late collecting nights i would have expected
it to be turning up more frequently rather than less frequently so why it disappeared is
due to something other than climate change i think
do you know it's food plant i think it's
feeds on various trees and shrubs as is the case with most of these live in sinopolia
but i'd have to look that up
the sinopolia quadrilineata is the most common species here in davis
um extremely common in some years the mid the early season ones are larger than the late season ones
which are often considerably smaller than the early season ones
but i i think that's just generations of the same moth and maybe the post plant quality is
and availability goes down later in the year
leucania
wajacana leucania is a difficult genus most of the species are very similar to one another
and i've been calling this wajacana on the basis of
um identification by somebody who is notorious for misidentifying moths but it does match a
descriptions of the moth on a website which has recently been deleted from the internet
oh no
what happened was there was a specialist in the group and he tried to
characterize the moth without using the genitalia as a character you know where i would have rather
seen the genitalia so i could confirm what they are but but now everything's gone so
lucca goniella californica and distincta is a very small gala kid and
might be a scavenger or might feed on like grains and seeds and things like that
it turns up in weird situation in some years is extremely common
um not so common this year so i don't know what's going on with it and i cannot tell the species apart
by looking at them whereas you see pictures of ones that haven't been dissected posted on the internet
so i don't how can you tell i don't trust those photos of undissected moths unless you know that they were
dissected um subsequently and they look like some species and other genera so this is kind of a
wastebasket i did dissect a few and i think all the ones in davis were one species or the other whereas
at cold canyon i found both species by up to ladies is a tiny um terra for it and
its abundance seems to vary from year to year but in general there seems to be fewer than in recent
years than i was getting some years ago but your data suggests that is this inclining or decline uh
declining the red is declining so that's what i sensed that it's in decline and some of them are
much smaller than others so it may be that host plant quality affects the size of them some moths are
very consistent in size or others not so much my machinia rufofascialis is a widespread
pyralid moth and it's turned up in varying amounts like you see it in the sierra
much more commonly than you do here in the valley and
it seemed to me that it disappeared for a while but i got a couple
you know more than two or three in recent years once again disappeared completely for the most part for
some time i don't know it's biology how's it going god hi grace hi how's it going cold yeah it's very
cold out well we're we'll quit around 10. momphus cephalanthi aloe was um is a tiny momphid and
momphids are specialists on uh evening primrose family but i just grab your stuff i don't know whether
cephalanthus is in that family or not let's see i'd have to look that up but i assume that's the food plant
uh it's in rubesi it's in what rubesi yeah an evening primrose family is on a gracie yeah
on a gracie i think yeah yeah so this is kind of an odd one and it's considerably smaller than the
other momphids half the size so and uh pal identified it you know and i asked him are you
sure and he says well it looks like it and that's so it's the name he used
momphid species 10 um i sent these off because i to the specialists on momphids
because i thought they were momphids or elakistis i'm sorry and he sent them right back said that they're
other momphids but probably in unidentified species and i think wagner reared this from
grasses in his yard in berkeley but i'm not 100 sure about that but uh it's varied in abundance over the
years but does seem to be in decline as your analyses suggests
the nofis cross the capitella is a tinea that might be introduced
and it's distinctive so this is one of the tineas that i'm certain of the identification
and
as your data suggests it does seem to have declined in recent years
let's finish this page and then we'll call it quits so sounds good methimna unipuncta
widespread species but studies studies in europe shows that there's both a
non-migratory and migratory populations of it and the migratory ones show up in the fall
and indeed i do get a lot of them in the fall but whether that's due to the native population
building up in numbers or migration ones coming in it's got a common name
yellow striped army worm or i think it's an army worm yeah and it's can be confused with lucania
okay and also moss in the genus alicia but
i'm fairly certain that most if not all have been correctly identified
and also the same for what i've been calling lucania which could be more than one species
and maybe a different one noctua pro nuvo is a recent
um invader invasive species and greg got one in his yard was the first one in davis a year before
i got it in my yard and it seemed to be increasing in abundance and now reaching more
more consistent numbers and it's prolificus um was introduced from europe and was making
almost predictable progress from the east coast where it first showed up across the u.s and then
suddenly jumped into california around 2000 2002 or so so it's a an invasive species that we detected
during this survey
nomophila neartica
was in pretty good numbers at the beginning of my survey then dropped off and then showed up again
from time from time to time feeds on low growing plants so it may be
maybe one that
abundance is related to rainfall so you know that's something you might look for if there's a correlation
there
and it does have a light long flight season
i think this year was a reasonably you know slightly more than average but
it's hard to know you know unless you index it for the frequency of collecting which i think your
program does yeah yeah these are just raw counts but yeah but you know also because it has a long flight
season you get the extremes are going to be out there but most of them fly mid-year
a label on the box awesome thank you so much that was okay we're making progress we're making progress
good