worried about the recording not working because it's so precious it's not working it is working
yeah yeah we're catching all of it i'm just tell you a species b there's two
named species non-determinata and i can't remember the other one
that wagner gave me the names for and there's one of each one from cold canyon one from my
backyard they both look very similar and they both look like what i'm calling calyptelia species b
so i suggest that you include non-determinata and the one from
let's see i might have that and the one from
and the other one as species b which is probably
two or more species
negundella is the other one
and that's negundella is the one as a record from davis and non-determinata is a record from cold
canyon
and wagner gave me names but he gave me a name in the past that made no sense because it was a
moth from florida or something so
you know he travels all over the place and sometimes forgets where he saw things
it's easy to put a name on things it's hard to put the right name on things
okay cameraria whislosinia there may be earlier specimens of this this feeds on
quercus whislosinia surprise which is valley live oak
and i may not have recorded all the early specimens
and it could be more than one species because
many of the cameraria species are very similar to one another
but the one that looks like at a cold canyon is on
quercus lobata or whatever and that isn't in davis so i think they're probably this is
probably one species and probably whislosinia but i've not dissected it it's tiny moth and
it's a demanding dissection caragina montana i think um there's one species that kind of resembles
it but i think they're all the same and there's two discrete generations per year
so i feel pretty good about that but
um caragina and there's species near it proxenus and spodoptera exigua seem to fluctuate in abundance
considerably from year to year and so the probability of collecting them probably increases when they're
having a big year and that may be real calcela ifitalis
feeds and
mud
wasps nests
oh interesting
and one year i had leaky sprinkler system and had a lot of mud
and that year i got a bunch of bud wasps nests under the ease to my house and i think they
may get in and feed on them after their
i don't know whether they feed on the larvae or feed on the debris that's left behind
but that could account for this abundance of them was the year my sprinkler system was leaking
interesting
kyanoti's okrio strigella feeds on sorrel i think
mm-hmm and uh it just shows up in low numbers and some years i get it some years not
but i do sometimes leave my porch light on and some i think i've seen it on my porch light
more often than i've seen it in my backyard
kyanoti's paloli um fees on oaks and i may have confused it there's one record of restio from early in the year and
males are easy to identify they have
a sex
linked
character
that you can't miss but the females
are hard to differentiate
from another species
and
folker heinrich who collects erin davis
has been calling them
occidentalis but i think his
i think that's erroneous okay
kyanoti's trichostola
um
it seems to overwinter as adults
and so you
if i weren't wasn't collecting earlier in the year i may have missed a lot of them
or late in the year
um
but
the fresh specimens seem to come out in the middle of the year so i guess it goes into
reproductive diaposism
and
i think it feeds on oaks but other things again there's a monograph on kyanoti's and the food plants of many of these are known
it looks like it's maybe declining in stubs and increasing in davis which is the first time i've seen that
could be because you know the oaks got hammered by the fires in cold canyon
it's a dark one
once you learn to recognize it it's easy to recognize but
it's hard to learn to recognize it
it doesn't you know it's kind of
nondescript but very consistent
so
copta trichimedia striata don't know much about it um i recorded this as a
buccolatrix
um
at both sites for a while and then realized it wasn't a buccolatrix i was always suspicious of it because
it was lacking one of the characters that buccolatrix has
what are we talking about copta trichimedia striata or similar species
and i'm pretty sure it's all one species but which species i don't know
so you confused it with
i thought it was a buccolatrix species
okay
so do you think in those early years not collecting it is
it would have been recorded as buccolatrix species one or two
i'm not sure which one i think species one at one locality and species two at the other
but i did make an effort to change all the records on all the data
on all of the spreadsheets
custa convexus centra strigaria
wait oh hold on one second so you corrected
you corrected the data these i think are all correct and all entered
so you think you really didn't see it in the very early years or you think that that's
well i may not have seen it
when i turned 65 which would have been 2010
um i was called in for driver's license
so i went to the optometrist and got glasses because i knew
i was going to flunk the
and all of a sudden small moths appeared at my sheet once again
so i don't think that i was as good at collecting small moths
in those few years prior to 2010
okay we'll deal with these grace i think we're just going to have to have like low
confident species models and higher confidence that sort of thing
yeah okay
um sorry i could we just go over these three again
coliophora sacramenta is a white coliophora it's one of the few that's very different from the others
and um
it has a i dissected a lot of the coliophora because i had a collection
of illustrations of the genitalia of almost all of the name species of which there are hundreds
and most of them didn't match anything but this one does seem to be a good match for sacramenta
and it's a white one so it's very distinctive
so every specimen that i collected was of a white coliophora was recorded as sacramenta
and we talked about peritana
so this is you think this is a real pattern where you just haven't seen it
i haven't seen any in recent years
so it could be that whatever it was feeding on
removed or it could be a parasite thing
uh do you so do we go over this essentially
i think we did but not on record so maybe if we can
oh yeah coliophora are external leaf miners if that makes it
uh-huh yeah
they make a um shelter
and there's a feeding tube as a feeding tube you know like if you have closed moths in your house
they make that little feeding shelter that they carry around
well they have a mobile shelter that's made from whatever they're feeding on
and groups of them with similar genitalia have similar feeding shelters
so some are kind of pistol shaped
and some are short tubes
some are long tubes
some are tapering tubes
and so on
and um
most leaf miners crash from time to time due to parasitism
so i don't know whether coleophora also crashes due to parasitism
or not but that might explain why this has disappeared
and then it takes a while to build up again
hey no
i mean
coleophora species b is the most common one around here
and i've been meaning to compare this to
a species that was introduced for control of
russian thistle
tumbleweed
is that what mario started
because that wasn't in the
that wasn't in the book of genitalia
no maybe
i think it's a different thistle
yeah
but this one
was in enormous numbers and seems to be in decline
recently
and if it is the one on tumbleweed
there's not as much tumbleweed around davis anymore
and whether it feeds on other um plants in the same family or not i don't know but
this is probably most coleophora are probably host specific or
narrowly um
what do they call it
oligo
i can't remember the terminology
oligophagus
yeah
i think
oh the technical terms that i don't use anymore
i never know how to say them either because i read them
yeah
not only that they redefine the term all the time and i can't keep up with it
costa convexo sensus sagaria getting back to that
i probably confused it with ortho nema obstepata in the early years
and they're somewhat difficult to tell apart
um
there are many that are clearly one or clearly the others but others are kind of difficult to tell apart
but it looks like in these early years you found them really rarely
you think that's real
but again this is one that a lot of records are early and late too so
mm-hmm
john would you just would you mind um going over the clepsis peritona again just for the recording
clepsis peritona again
just for the recording
okay
clepsis peritona is
polyphagus
feeds on low growing plants
and in the back corner i took out the lawn in a section of my backyard
and for a while i was
growing tomatoes which never bore fruit
and a number of garlic which never divided into cloves and a number of other things
so i kind of abandoned urban farmer
and it's gotten weedy and it's gotten overrun by this thimbleberry
and so i think that's what it's feeding on my yard and maybe that's why it's become common
but also there's a lot of late records for it
like it's the most common species in my yard in late October and early November
i mean i've been getting them the last few nights and sometimes multiples
where everything else is
very occasionally and
just one or two
got it
yeah
thank you
um maybe if we get through all of the seas we could take a break because we are all the time
i'm willing to stay as long as you would like if you're okay staying but it's
i have to go do you have to go
um
we have writing group but i can skip some of it probably
and you can keep recording
after your break and
maybe you and john can even if it's possible find another time this week to try and keep going
yeah and you can use our phone to call africa if you want
well she's going to use her own phone so
um
yeah let's finish out the seas
okay i'm at city of latiferiana
that's the filbert moth
and
here it probably feeds mainly in acorns
oh cute
and
i don't seem to get as many as greg does and greg has
oaks in his yard and i don't so that could explain it but it shows up throughout the year
and
i don't know whether it's in decline or not but
all i can say is greg records it much more often in a much bigger numbers than i do so
i think because i don't have oaks around
it's in decline in both habitats
pardon me
it's in decline in uh stebs too probably the fire thing
oh
yeah could be
um
i don't know what other
well it's called the filbert moth so obviously it gets in other kind of nuts and kernels and so forth
so i don't know what the full range of its host species is
city of pominella is
the
codling moth
and i don't think
you know this is a pest species and
and
the numbers vary from year to year in my yard and i
it's
didn't seem to be very common this year and
uh
this suggests a kind i
i don't think i've ever seen it at
um
cold canyon
i don't think i have one record for it
no you don't
so
it's a pest species
it's an introduced pest species
and it seems to be
closely associated with orchard crops
diastictus fracturalis feeds on grasses
presumably
and
so here's a case where there's one that seems to be increasing
in
abundance
whereas those two agriphalus species
which are also sod moths are
in decline so
it could be that one is replacing the other
you know because the introduced lawn moth which we don't see at cold canyon
has
pretty much displaced the native
uh
lawn moth or sod moth
do we want to
finish up with the diagrammas before you guys take a break
diagram
diagramia california area is
uh
feeds on conifer maybe more than one species
this is one even though there was a recent
monograph on
this
group of geometric moths
um
this was one section
that wasn't satisfactorily
resolved
it's somewhat variable
and i've been calling
uh oh
i just
i'm talking about the wrong one
california area i think is
on the
and
um
i'd have to look up what the food plant is
this is not the conifer one that's
multiple species
but it could be that at cold canyon
the small ones have been recorded
as
delictata
is that one in there
okay
i think i started recording it later
um
and
i did some dissections
i did some dissections of these
to determine that we have it
and
i only had a few records of this
muscariata
in the early years and both of them
have
increased in numbers
you think that's real
yeah
in the habitat
okay
i mean not only has the occurrences
increased but the numbers have increased
yeah it's interesting like
for
muscataria
muscariata
yeah
yeah muscariata
it looks like it went up a lot
like
maybe
yeah
and then
it's a really nice curve here
one of them
is known to feed on
lotus
and the other one
i can't remember now
i'm surprised that i can remember any of this to tell you the truth
yeah
it's incredible
you have a lot in your brain
yeah
diagramia
aerorata
looks very similar to
diagramia
neptaria
and
i think i
i did some dissections
and i think that i am
correctly identifying them all
but
mistakes could have been made
and neither one of them
aerorata seems to be the
more common one in my yard
and i don't know what the situation is
with neptaria
i'm not sure that they're calling it neptaria
that's still anymore
maybe plamolata
plamolata feeds on willow
so plamolata and
neptaria are both in your data set
do you think that they are distinct
no
plamolata i used to call something else
but i can't remember the name
but we have the other one here
and
what's
what's the other one neptaria
i get neptaria in my yard
but not as often as
aerorata
and it's
i guess it didn't make this
aerorata is in
yeah
it didn't
it didn't make the charts
oh
yeah it didn't make the charts
so i don't have
so do you think that
aerorata and neptaria
and plamolata
do you think that we should lump them
you think they're distinct
plamolata is very distinct from the other two
but aerorata and neptaria
are somewhat similar
and i've been
i did some dissections
and then i
after dissecting a number
where there were
seemed to be differences
which worked
i started
sorting them
on the basis
okay
of similarity
to dissected specimens
but when i look at
illustrations online
um
they don't necessarily agree
with
the way i'm sorting them
but the ones online
haven't been dissected
so
they could be
misidentified
well i'm
i'm trusting you
john
i think we should lump those
there were a lot of errors
uh you know
or in the early days
of moth photographers group
and they've been
getting straightened out
but now we have
i naturalists
with all of these
amateur
lepidopterists
posting pictures
of things
and it's
you know
it's good that we get
the records
but it's bad
that we get
unsubstantiated one
and
you can go in there
and identify them
and make them research grade
do you do that ever
well
um
some people have
but i don't post things
on i naturalist
oh god
that's a shame
grace
before i forget
i do think that
um
we're gonna have to go back
to the original data set
and recapture
um
like for instance
iraida didn't make it
into that data set
but
because it doesn't have
no iraida did
neptaria didn't make it
in davis
oh okay
right
i thought it would have
had enough records
but i guess i didn't
so we'll have to go back
and rescue those
if we're gonna lump them
do you see what i'm saying
okay so we're
we're lumping
iraida and
neptaria
together
i think so
okay
i don't know that it would
change things very much
but
and
it probably won't
do you see what i'm saying
about the original data set
mm-hmm
okay
well we'll decide what to do
with all of these
we'll just like
uh
come up with strategies
and run them by john
um
okay i have to run
this is so
well you know
one time run through
may not be enough
the data