I'm just going to keep recording here.
Okay, yeah, so maybe we can go through a little bit faster, even though...
Okay, Acontea coccolettia, I think all the...
This is a very distinctive moth.
All the records are here, and they're all correctly recorded.
And I think it feeds on something in the Malvesi family, but I'm not sure.
Wagner told me, and I promptly forgot.
But if you want to know Wagner, Wagner suspects what the food plant is.
May, no, I don't know.
You're taking notes, right?
So I don't need to do that, okay.
Acrobasis tricholorella at Cold Canyon seems to be mainly on Toyon,
but I don't have Toyon in my neighborhood.
But it's somewhat common throughout the years,
and more common some years than others.
I don't know what it's feeding on my yard.
I have a birch tree, and I think maybe that,
but Toyon's in the Rosaceae family,
so it could be something in the Rosaceae family.
I don't know enough about its life history,
but you could probably look it up.
There is a Mona fascicle that includes this,
so it would be there, in which case it's probably also online.
Adelphagrotus indeterminata,
I think some of the early specimens
were erroneously recorded as Per-Abogrotus.
Per-Abogrotus formalis and Adelphagrotus indeterminata
both have a black collar.
The pronotum is black.
So early years are suspect.
Okay.
But once I started recording them as separate species,
the Abogrotus were all lumped together
because it got, we were calling it one thing,
and it got split into several species.
And once I learned how to,
then they started to be identified correctly.
And about the same time,
I recognized indeterminata as separate from Per-Abogrotus.
So the early years are suspect.
All the records are late in the year for Adelphagrotus.
So any early records are wrong.
Aglasa caprealis is a pantry moth.
So it's sometimes a pest of stored products.
And I think it's the only species we have here in Davis,
but there is another Aglasa that looks very much like it.
So potentially it's two species,
but I think it's all one.
It looks like it dropped off at the end here.
Like someone treated their pantry moths or something?
I can't say,
except maybe it's because I've been better
about sweeping up my patio
over which I hang my sheet.
Got it.
Okay.
Pantry moths don't tend to be collected outdoors as much.
Yeah, we might want to strike that one
just from the record,
like just strike it out of the data set
because it's not an outdoor dwelling moth.
Okay.
But we get an Aglasa at Cold Canyon,
which is somewhat similar,
but I don't think it's the same moth.
Okay.
Agryphala anseps flies only late in the year
and it feeds on native grasses, I believe.
I think it's a sod moth.
And I haven't seen it the last couple of years.
But Greg's been reporting it from East Davis,
although this year he only reported
one of the other Agryphala attenuatus.
Same life history for attenuatus.
And it's disappeared the last couple of years too.
And that may be due to
some of what the city's doing,
you know, and landscaping and so forth,
plus developing to the north.
I have no idea.
All speculation.
Agryphala is a black cutworm
pest species.
I think it's fairly,
I get it every year and throughout the year,
but the numbers vary.
So I think this is pretty good representation.
Amiolois transitella,
you know,
this is the one where I've been recording some
as ore species in here.
And this year I got some that are
pretty much intermediate.
So I think they're all
A. transitella.
So if you include those in the data,
maybe it will change the pattern.
But this year it was so common
that I think it's,
that this is real.
It is becoming more abundant
and more frequent.
And I get records
throughout the year.
This is a pest species,
but not a major pest species.
It's an orchard crop species.
So maybe,
you know,
this year I had a good crop of pluots.
So maybe it fed on my pluots.
I don't know.
Hmm.
Inarcia lineatella.
Okay.
Oh, okay.
This is a
Delicaea
that's called the
I think it feeds in
that it's fruit tree,
tips of fruit trees
or something like that.
So
I get a few every year.
I can't say whether it's
more common or less common.
This year I didn't get very many
and
some years I got more
in the past.
Anna vitrinella
ocularia
and or
Pampanaria.
We
can't agree
on what species
we have
and
in Powell's
book
Oppler wrote
if you're not sure
you need to dissect them.
Well,
I could dissect them
but I don't
have any illustrations
of his genitalia
so I haven't bought it.
I remember you talking
about that one last time.
But I think
Pampanaria
is smaller.
But again,
this is one
where there's overlap
in the size
so I can't be sure.
So
we have that
uncertainty reflected
in the name
which is good.
Well,
I called them
Pampanaria
when I first started
collecting them
and then later
I started calling them
ocularia
and now
I've been calling
them and or
because I'm just
not sure.
Do you think
that this
do you think
in the early years
you just weren't
clocking them?
No, I didn't get
any in the
I didn't record
earlier years
but I don't know
if they were
a recent arrival
or
I just was collecting
I think it's one
that gets
no, I can
I do remember
that when I got it
I said, oh
I know that
from Cold Canyon
and I'd never seen
it in my yard before
so I didn't get it
in the early years
but I didn't collect
too frequently
in the early years.
And this is I think
one of those cases