so if it's a matter of purging okay so this is john talking about the moths and the data that
grace has on them on the x-axis is year and on the y-axis is day positives which
is simply the number of times that john saw the moth and we have not adjusted on the y-axis for
the number of times john went out per year so he's going to talk about each moth and what we need
to know about the trends that we're seeing do you want to start with davis yes okay acaira rantalis
and acaira
occidentalis which you don't have here are two very similar species
and rantalis tends to be smaller and
has a more blurred pattern whereas occidentalis is larger you didn't plot occidentalis i see
occidentalis should it be here and we're missing it well we we do have it at davis i do have records
for it at davis but only one or two okay yeah i see so it may not be frequent
the genitalia are different and you can positively identify it by genitalia so i did a number of
um dissections and then since then i've been sorting them out primarily based on size and color but
there's a lot of them that still remain equivocal and those i continue to record as either or
so as a kyra species one of the two above
so early rec early ones if i didn't retain the specimen
may not have been recorded i may not have made an effort to identify it so i always recorded it as
uh one of the two above so maybe we should uh change this to a kyra spa
and well you could lump them all together for all three
bins so the rentalis occidentalis
i think a kyra occidentalis is one of them is known as the garden
something or other so it's a widespread moth the other one is strictly
western and i think that's occidentalis and rantalis is known to be
on alfalfa so i think the years that they grew alfalfa in the fields to the north of where i live
it probably was more common so in general the
number and frequency of them is probably correlated with whether they're
growing alfalfa or not and the small ones which is rantalis seem
to be far more common than the larger ones
and at cold canyon i think mostly i got larger ones
because they don't grow any alfalfa in there but it probably feeds on other things because
um they're somewhat of a generalist okay
should we check the recording and make sure it's working is that what you're thinking
yeah is it still recording do we know are you okay yeah it's still working