Taking off now?
No, I'm just going to use the bathroom, but you can keep going.
Yeah.
Okay.
Epinodia postiliana, postiliana, sisquioansis.
That's a mouthful.
Yeah.
The reason why I kept the subspecific name here is the, there was a, he's now a professor
at Mississippi State who did, as his PhD project, a revision of North American species of Epinodia
that, as far as I know, was never published.
And he believed that sisquioansis was a distinct species from Pulsatana.
So that's why I kept it here.
And the basis for that is there's a wing fold that is longer in the coastal ones than,
which are sisquioansis, than the other parts of the range.
I've reared it.
It feeds on, what is it?
Arbutus, you know, Virgin's Valor is the common name.
I don't know what Janus it said anymore.
Pardon me.
Wait, is it this?
No, not Madrone.
Oh.
Virgin's Bower?
Trillian Arbya.
Clematis?
What is it?
Yeah.
Clematis, yeah.
Which is, you know, that's that vine that kind of gets up and goes over other trees and shrubs.
So, I think it may be, because the food plant itself is supported by other shrubs,
it may then, if the shrubs get burned out and the fire decline,
it can be confused with those two species of decodes that we discussed earlier.
These are all Ola through time tortrices, but the palpi are very different.
But if you're not, if you don't examine the palpi, or if the palpi are broken off,
you might confuse them for one another.
Palpi often get broken in the killing vial.
So, that's a problem.
Epinodia signiferana.
I think this is one that feeds on willow.
I'm not sure.
And this is one that has, it's kind of controversial as to whether it's a good species or not,
but I'm using the name that Jerry gave me for ones that look like what he calls signiferana.
Ethmia arctistaphylilla.
Ethmias are sometimes put in their own family,
but I think in the checklist, they're included with depressority.
And Ethmia arctistaphylilla is one of these species that's misnamed
because it doesn't feed on arctistaphylis.
It feeds on eriodiction.
And you can find adults flying during the day, well, during the night.
The two species, the two common nocturnal species, which is this and the next one,
are somewhat similar to one another.
Plus, another species, which I have not recorded at Cold Canyon,
but it has been collected at McLaughlin, so it's probably, it could be there,
but I never saw one that I recorded as that other species,
the name of which doesn't come to me.
So,
Disco strigella feeds on circocarpus.
So it's widely distributed because circocarpus is quite widely distributed,
whereas eriodiction is not so widely distributed,
so arctistaphylilla has a narrower distribution.
Arctistaphylilla has seasonal forms,
and one form is very different from Disco strigella,
where the other one is similar to Disco strigella,
so they can be confused with one another,
and they also can be confused with other species.
But I think they're mostly recorded correctly,
but because of the similarity,
I can't say that every one was recorded correctly.
Eublima minima is a very small noctuaid
that feeds on
Pearly Everlasting.
Oh, I have no idea.
I can't think of this.
Anaphylus.
Yeah, Anaphylus.
Oh, oh, yeah, yeah, no,
I want the phone book because it's solid paper.
Yeah, and, you know,
there's another plant that looks like Anaphylus.
They're emergency plants.
Naphthalion.
With a G.
And it may also feed on that,
I don't know.
Yeah, the plants are almost identical,
and, you know,
you have to pull them up
and look at whether they have a tuberous root
or not to tell them apart.
I get this in Davis as well,
but it's a small moth,
and it has a peculiar lobe
on the trailing edge of the wing,
so it's...
So the base of it is wider than,
you know, makes an abrupt narrowing
to the more apical portions of it,
but it's easy to forget
how to identify this,
that hind wing sometimes
is the reminder to...
It reminds me what it is.
It looks like you've seen it more commonly
in recent years.
It could be,
because, you know,
Annapolis is a weedy plant
and probably, you know,
gets choked out by weedy grasses
if there hasn't been a fire in a long time,
and it may succeed quickly after fire,
but, you know,
I don't know enough about
the post-fire ecology
to make these, you know,
if you're going to be focusing
on what happens after fire,
you know,
there's probably somebody here
on campus
who has some good notions
of what's going on.
You know,
we know that certain plants
stump shoot after fire
and another one's...
Herodiction for a while,
you know,
was one of the first things
that came back after the fire.
This is a really good point
that we should look and see.
Let me talk to Andrew Latimer
about that stuff.
Euceracea castella
is a...
Sorry, the euclina,
did you talk about?
Euceracea castella.
Oh, I'm out of order.
Okay.
Yeah.
This is a plutelid.
I'm not sure whether
plutelid is recognized
as a family.
You know,
some people treat it
as a good family.
Some people do not.
Or,
you know,
Ipsilophidae.
These are sometimes
combined
and sometimes not.
So...
Castella feeds on...
plants and caperfoliaceae.
It's iffy.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
So...
Like honeysuckles and things?
Yeah.
And I have collected it
during the day,
but I don't know
if it's ones
that I've just scared up
or were actually flying
during the day.
It flies,
I think,
one generation
per year
and I'm...
probably native.
Almost certainly native.
There's another species
there that has
the same wing shape
and it's kind of
tannish looking
and then there's one
that's intermediate
and I don't know
whether the intermediate
looking one
is at Cold Canyon
or not,
but if it is,
I would have called it
one or the other
and didn't record it
correctly.
Euclina molisseria
is a large
geometria
and I don't know
very much about
its biology,
but it's easy
to recognize,
so I think
every individual
has been recorded
correctly.
Can we go back
to the Euceraceae?
Euceraceae?
Euceraceae.
What is the species
that looks like it?
I can't recall.
Could you...
Would it be
in the dataset?
Just type in
euceraceae
and see what pops up.
Yeah.
I do have records
for the darker one
that it didn't
make the list.
Yeah, exactly.
But you're saying
basically that...
Castella is...
Is it possible
they're a species
complex?
You said there's
an intermediate block.
No, I doubt
that these are...
that the three
species that are
recognized now
are different forms
of the same species,
but I don't...
But I don't know
that for certain.
Securella?
Yeah, Securella
is the other one,
and then there's
one that
doesn't seem
to be listed there.
Oh, that's my list,
though.
Yeah.
So those are
the two species
that I recorded.
And then the one
that's intermediate,
I think it's called
like Intermediella
or something.
It's a name
that suggests
that it's kind
of in between.
And I think
Powell described
that species,
and the paper
may provide
some insight
as to whether
these are...
whether there's
strong evidence
that they're
separate species
or not.
But I think
they feed on
the same thing
and they're
all fly
at the same time.
But that's
always a problem,
especially if
you're
typological
in what is
and what is
not a species
rather than
using other
evidence.
We're waiting
for the DNA
evidence.
Well, I'm sure
your collections
will be used
for that
at some point.
Eudonia.
So, this
would be the
first one
that I can...
I had a notion
for a while
that Eudonia
was one of
the species
that feeds
on moss,
but I think
that's incorrect.
And I think
Eudonia
rectilineida
feeds on
oaks.
And it's
the more
common species
at Cold Canyon
and very
distinct from
the others.
Spencer
Rye
is the
most common
one in
Davis.
And
I don't know.
I didn't look...
You know,
there is a
monograph.
One of the
first Mona
monographs
covers this
genus.
and there
may be some
post-plant
records in it,
but if I did
look it up,
it's lost
to antiquity.
the other
Eudonia
there,
I'm surprised
it didn't
make the list.
Is it?
Oh,
Echo.
Yeah.
And that
one's harder
to identify.
And I
brought some
home to
dissect and
never got
around to it.
And I'm
not sure
that every
individual
has been
recorded.
and
those that
I did
record,
I'm not
sure if
I didn't
mistake
them for
other
species
of
Eudonia,
but even
other species
in different
genera.
So
the ones
that I
comfortable
in identifying
as
Rectilinia.
Spenceri
looks like
another
species,
but
Powell
and I
were in
agreement
that
what I'm
calling
Spenceri
are
and not
the
similar
looking
species.
But we
could both
be wrong.
You,
Japanulatrix,
like Japanulatrix,
is a
ceanothus
feeder.
it's
kind of
a
pale
moth,
even
towards
whitish
and
throughout
the year
somewhat
common.
eupathesia
nevidata.
This
is a
conundrum
because
in the
nevidata
complex
of
species,
nevidata
and related
species,
there's
one
that
is a
possibility
called
implorata,
which I've
recorded.
One
called
starts
with a
C,
cestata,
I think
it is.
And then
one
called
well,
the
genitalia
are similar
to one
another.
And in
some of
those
species,
there's
characters
that
differentiate
the
females,
but not
the
males.
And
then
it
turned
out
let me
backtrack
a little.
There have
been three
monographs
on
eupathesia.
One was
by
McDonough
and I
think that
was either
in the
late 30s
or in
the 40s.
And it
covered all
the species
with good
illustrations of
genitalia and
some other
characters.
And then
there was a
guy named
Bolte in
Canada who
covered only
the Canadian
species.
And he not
only looked at
genitalia and
everything, but
he had
illustrations of
the head and
antennal
characters and
things like
that, which
sometimes were
diagnostic.
So that in
some ways was
the best.
And then most
recently,
Ferris, who
is an
engineer, I
think he
taught
engineering in
Wyoming, but
was a
butterfly collector
for years.
but he's
an advanced
collector, and
he revisited the
genus again.
And the
problem with
the first one
by McDonough is
the photographs
of the adults
were printed on
this horrible,
poor quality,
grainy paper,
so they're not
distinct looking.
and they're
black and
white, and
they're terrible
quality.
So Ferris, at
the very least,
provided better
photographs, and
he photographed the
genitalia rather
than drawings of
them, which has
pros and cons.
One, it's more
realistic, but you
don't always
emphasize the
diagnostic characters.
So, you
know, when I
have trouble, I
kind of go to
all of them.
What turned
out, when I
looked at
Ferris's
photographs of
what I have
been calling
Implorata, I
obviously made
them, I
don't, I'm
not in
agreement.
And what I
called Implorata
was based on
the written
description that
McDonough made
of Implorata.
So now I'm
thinking that it
would be best to
just call them
to call
Nevidata
Implorata
the questionable
one, Sestata,
and there's one
that's like
Sestatoides or
something like
that.
Lump them all
together and just
call them Nevidata
or, you know,
or Nevidata or
related species
like I did
here.
But that's a
bit, you know,
Bolte couldn't
figure it out
when he did
it and he
was, I
thought, the
most careful
of the bunch.
So careful he
went on to
working on
flies, which,
you know,
sends most
people running
for the exits.
Okay, I'm
going to stop
this because